theplayerslottery.com 2012-05-04

# Privacy Policy.docx

Privacy Policy

* * *

Your privacy and the protection of your personal information are very important to The Players Lottery™ (hereinafter called “TPL”). We are committed to maintaining the confidentiality of the personal information collected by us in order to allow you access to www.theplayerslottery.com.  We safeguard your personal information utilizing the best in class software, hardware architecture, techniques, methods and procedures. 

The purpose of this privacy policy is to enable you to understand how we collect, store, use and safeguard information relating to you and for you to understand your rights in relation to that information. 

What information is collected what is it used for?   
As part of the TPL Registration process, we will ask you to provide us with personal information, which will include your real first and last name, a ‘display name’ of your own choosing (for use in group tickets or forums/chat), your postal address, your e-mail address, telephone number and a password.  As well, you will also be required to provide information to verify that you are at least 18 years old or older in jurisdictions in which the minimum age for use of the TPL services is greater than 18.  You will also need to supply information to certify that you reside in a jurisdiction which allows online gambling. 

In order to make deposits or withdrawals, purchase lottery tickets, receive prizes and facilitate refunds, it may be necessary to collect other information from you such as credit card numbers or banking information.  This is entirely dependent on what methods you choose to pay for your purchases and receive your prizes.

We will use your personal information to send you critical administrative information that directly affects you or your account, such as receipts from purchases, notifications of unusual activity in your account, etc.  This information is not solicitous in nature and you may not opt-out of the critical administrative notifications. 

Other information, such as our newsletter, is not mandatory and you have a choice as to whether to receive it or not (Opt-in or Opt-out).  If you no longer wish to receive non-mandatory communication from TPL or its partners, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included with each message.

We also use your information to provide you with customer support services when you contact us with a question or complaint. 

Additionally, the personal information that TPL collects from you during your use of the Site may be used by TPL to:

  1. verify that you are permitted to access and/or use the Site; 
  2. assist you with your access to and/or use of the Site, and verify your entitlement to any prize or giveaway and any other Site benefit; 
  3. investigate unauthorized use of your username or your password; 
  4. assist TPL and its service providers with any aspect or operation of the Site; 
  5. administer its marketing campaigns; 
  6. provide a better experience for visitors to the Site, improve products and services, help TPL better understand its user’s needs;
  7. only with your prior approval, bring other products and services to your attention; 
  8. conduct research, including compiling of gaming statistics, for TPL internal use only; 
  9. administer responsible gaming programs including the Voluntary Self Exclusion program; 
  10. simplify signup for any other Services, or offers by TPL; 
  11. share with TPL’s service providers for the above noted purposes as deemed necessary by TPL; display the name, alias, location and age of winners and chat participants. 
  12. Players personal information will be kept on TPL’s secured servers

Players are able to change account details and opt in or out of various promotions by selecting the “Edit Profile” option under the My Profile tab from their Member’s Homepage. 

Confidentiality   
TPL undertakes substantial efforts to protect the confidentiality of the identity, preferences and other information it has collected about individual Players and will not knowingly allow access to this information to anyone outside TPL, other than to the Player or as described in this Privacy Policy. TPL has made a substantial investment in its servers, databases, backup, firewall and encryption technologies to protect the information collected by TPL. 

All TPL employees are required to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy provides that employees are obligated to keep Player information strictly confidential. This obligation continues once an employee has left our Company. 

You should also do your part in protecting your information. Your TPL Player password is confidential and we recommend that you not divulge it to anyone or enable others to discover it. 

Limits of Confidentiality   
Legally Required Disclosures: Due to the existing legal, regulatory and security environment, TPL may be required, under certain circumstances, to disclose personally identifiable information about our Players. TPL will use its best reasonable efforts to limit such disclosure to the following: where TPL believes in good faith that it is required to do so in response to a subpoena, warrant or other legal process; or where reasonably necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities to preserve and/or enforce TPL rights. Further, we can, and you authorize us to, disclose your Player identification, name, street address, city, state, post code, country, phone number, e-mail, and company to third party agents of TPL as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, money laundering, intellectual property infringement, piracy or other unlawful activity or activity that may expose us to legal liability. 

Who receives your information?   
In addition to legally required disclosures as explained above, we may disclose your personal information to our employees, employees of other companies related to or affiliated with The Players Lottery and to third party service providers who use your personal information to provide services to us in respect of your being a Player with TPL.  All recipients of your personal information shall be bound by applicable data protection laws to keep your personal information private at no less a level than that by which we are bound. 

Your rights in relation to your information  
We aim to keep our information about you as accurate as possible.  You can write to us at any time to review, change or obtain a copy of your information, or you review and/or make changes to your information yourself from your Member’s Homepage under My Profile.  In order to contact us regarding your information please e-mail support@theplayerslottery.com. 

Security  
TPL takes every effort to protect our customers' information both on and offline.  Sensitive data is encrypted using the best encryption software in the industry and is further protected by a robust firewall.  Offline, your data is protected by a strict Privacy Policy for our employees.  Only approved and qualified staff has access to our secured databases and in order to perform specific lottery-related tasks, each must first provide a personalized password prior to being allowed access to customer data.  Once logged into the secure database, employee actions are “key-logged”, which allows us to track who accessed what data and what they did with the data exactly. All customer data is stored in our secure servers within a locked cabinet inside a secure hosting facility.  No one within the secure facility has access to our data.

Use of Cookies

We may send you a temporary cookie when you visit the TPL website. A cookie is a text-only string of information that we place in your computer's browser so that we can remember who you are when you revisit us or to track affiliate sales, your Share the Wealth Network, etc. We may use the data generated from cookies to compile statistical data on your use of our website to help us to improve user experience. You are not obliged to accept the cookie from us and you have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. 

Log Files  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

Links  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that TPL is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by TPL. 

Service Updates and Purchase, Withdrawal and Refund Receipts  
TPL will on occasion and when necessary notify customers by email of any site and service announcements and updates that may concern them.  As well, TPL will send by email receipts for all purchases, refunds and withdrawals. Members are not able to unsubscribe these notifications, which are not promotional in nature. We also communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regard to issues relating to their account via email or phone.

Email Alerts and RSS Feeds  
Users have the option of requesting email alerts and/or RSS Feeds for things such as breaking news, lottery sell-out status, winning tickets, etc. These services are voluntarily requested by the user and can be disabled at any time via the User’s Member Homepage.

Our Mail Service for Refer-A-Friend, Lottery Club Communications and Gift Certificate Wizard.  
If a user elects to use our mail service to inform a friend about our site, or to form a Lottery Club or to give a Gift Certificate, we will ask them for their friends’ email addresses. TPL will automatically send the friends a one-time email for these purposes only, as specified and requested by you, and we store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. The friend may contact TPL at [ support@theplayerslottery.com](mailto:support@theplayerslottery.com) to request the removal of this information from the database. 

Consent to Privacy Policy   
By opening an Account with TPL you agree to the terms of this PRIVACY POLICY. We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy and encourage you to periodically review it. If we change our privacy policy we will post the changes on this page.  Your continued use of the TPL services constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates. 

Email: support@theplayerslottery.com

Mailing Address:    
The Players Lottery®

c/o Titan Gaming Ltd,  
Vincenti Buildings, 

14/19 (Suite No. 1027) Strait Street, 

Valletta VLT1432, 

Malta

Privacy Policy last revised: 10th March, 2011 

Copyright © 2012 The Players Lottery® can be contacted by email at support@theplayerslottery.com
